

# **ABOUT ME**

Gender: male.

Date of Birth: 22/01/1987. Nationality: Iranian. Marital Status: Single.

Back-end programmer and web developer with 5 years of experience in the IT industry. Skilled at gathering and analyzing requirements, designing and implementing complex back-end functionality, creating optimized databases, and performing unit testing to resolve bugs and issues and fluid understanding of many programming languages and frameworks including JavaSE, JavaEE, Spring Framework, OracleAdf, and Node.js. Worked with a large team of GUI and Java developers to maintain and improve company projects as well as banking systems and enterprise applications software (EAS).

# **SOCIAL NETWORK**

### LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abed-alavi/

### WHATSAPP:

https://wa.me/989392842281

## **CONTACT**

#### WEBSITE:

http://www.abedalavi.ir

## E-MAIL:

alavi.khorasani@gmail.com

## **ADDRESS:**

Mashhad, Iran

PHONE:

# ABDOLLAH ALAVI KHORASANI MOGHADDAM

Senior Java EE Developer

# **CAPABILITY STATEMENTS**

- Extensive programming experience in Java core concepts such as OOP Concepts, Collections Framework, Exception Handling, Multi-Threading, Serialization.
- Hands-on experience in the design of JavaEE architecture Web Applications, using technologies such as Java, Spring MVC, Hibernate, JSP, JDBC, Servlets.
- Familiar with various web services including Oracle WebLogic, Apache Tomcat, IBM WebSphere, RedHat WildFly.
- Experienced in relational databases like Oracle 19c, MS SQL server, Functions, Views, Indexes, Triggers, and other complex queries, as well as NoSQL databases like MongoDB.
- Expertise in Spring Framework development with Spring Boot, Spring Core, Spring Security, Spring Web MVC, Spring data JPA.
- Familiar with different Operating Systems including Microsoft windows and Linux (Redhat based).
- Familiar with build automation tools for java include Maven, Gradle and Ant.
- Experienced in Java API's including Oracle ADF, Junit, Log4j, SLF4J, Hibernate ORM, Jasper Report.
- Deep understanding of web technologies: HTML 5, XHTML, CSS 3, DOM, XML, XSLT, JavaScript, Ajax, jQuery, Bootstrap, JSON.
- Experienced in programing and scripting with PHP, SQL, PL/SQL, C++, C#, CLR, Regular Expression.
- Experienced in programing with Node.js including Express.js, socket.io oracledb.js modules.

## **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor** Khorasan University

In Computer Hardware Technology Engineering

Mashhad, Iran 2010, 2012

Associate Azad University

In Computer Engineering (Software)

Neishabur, Iran 2006, 2009

### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

### **JAVA CORE**

OOP Concepts	•••••
<b>Exception Handling</b>	•••••
Multi-Threading	•••••
Input and Output	•••••
Serialization	•••••
Collections	•••••
JDBC	•••••

### **JAVA EE**

Servlet	•••••
JSP	•••••
EJP	•••••
JPA	

### **WEB SERVERS:**

Oracle WebLogic	●●●●○○○
Apache Tomcat	••••0000
IBM WebSphere	••••0000
RedHat WildFly	••••0000

### **DATABASES**:

Oracle Database	•••••
MS SQL Server	••••0000
MySQL	•••••
MongoDB	••••0000

## **SPRING FRAMEWORK:**

Spring Core	•••••
Spring Boot	•••••
Spring MVC	•••••
Spring Data JPA	•••••
Spring Security	•••••

# OS PLATFORMS:

Microsoft Windows 10	•••••
Microsoft Windows	•••00000
Server	
Linux	•••••

### **BUILD AUTOMATIONS**

Maven	•••••
Gradle	•••••
Ant	••••0000

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# JavaEE Developer Melal Bank (Credit Company)

Mashhad, Iran — 2018-now

https://bank-melal.ir/

Melal Credit Institution is one of the approved Credit Institutes of Central Bank of IRAN (CBI) with more than 2 million customers which providing all banking Services to customers including Mobile/Internet Banking, E-Payment services, Core Banking Services through the branches and other useful services.

#### Some of my duties included the followings:

- Developing and maintaining monitoring systems with Node.js and Socket.io from database data.
- Developing and deploying various Restful web services with Spring Boot and Node.js.
- Developing web applications for banking systems with JavaEE technologies including Spring Web MVC.
- PL/SQL programming including Functions and Procedures.

# Software Technician Sazgar Company

Mashhad, Iran — 2015-2018

http://sazaar.com/

Sazgar Argham Company was founded in 1990 based on strong technical and professional support and started its extensive services with the help of expert staff in IT industry. Sazgar Argham is the member of Iran's High Council of Informatics and Iranian ICT Guild Organization (IIG) and has license for industrial activities in personal computers. Now, this company is building a company that produces personal computers. Sazgar Argham Company is an inventor of warranty in Iran and supports a wide distribution network throughout of country.

### Some of my duties included the followings:

- Laptop and Tablet technician included ASUS, Acer, Lenovo.
- ASUS RMA System Manager.
- Diagnosing and repairing computer hardware part including Laptop, Tablet, Motherboard, HDD and so forth.

# IT Manager Sakhtar Sanat Barsava

Mashhad, Iran — 2013-2015

Sakhtar sanat barsava is a company in Mashhad industrial city that Manufacturing home appliances.

### Some of my duties included the followings:

- IT Manager including software and hardware maintenance.
- Database DBA including maintaining and backup databases.

### IDE

IntelliJ IDEA	•••••
VS Code	•••••
Jdeveloper	•••••

### **ARCHITECRUTE**

Microservices	•••••
MVC	•••••
TDD	●●●●○○○○
RAD	•••••000

### **OTHERS JAVA API**

Oracle ADF	•••••
Unit Testing (Junit)	•••••
Integration Testing	•••••
Log4J	•••••
SLF4J	•••••
Hibernate	•••••
Jasper Reports	••••0000

### **WEB LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES**

HTML 5	•••••
CSS 3	•••••
Java\$cript	•••••
JQuery	•••••
Bootstrap	•••••
XML	•••••
JSON	•••••
REST	•••••
AJAX	•••••
Git	•••••

### **OTHER PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

Node.js	•••••
SQL	•••••
PL/SQL	•••••
C#	••••0000
C++	••••0000
T-SQL	●●●○○○○
CLR	••••0000
Regular Expression	•••••
Socket Programming	•••••
PHP	••••0000

# **PERSONAL SKILLS**

Analytical	•••••
Leadership	•••••
Motivation	•••••
Team working	•••••
Positive	••••••
Interactivity	•••••

# **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking	Listening
Persian	•••••	•••••	•••••	•••••
English	•••••	•••••	•••••	•••••

# **CERTIFICATION**

# 1. COMP102.1x: Introduction to Java Programming – Part 1

• Issuing Organization: edx.org

• Issue Date: 12/2019

• Credential URL:

https://courses.edx.org/certificates/14ad37197f56440baa9d5df914b59277

# 2. ASP.NET Developers

- Issuing Organization: Iran Technical & Vocational Training
- Issue Date: 2009

### 3. Oracle DBA

- Issuing Organization: Iran Technical & Vocational Training
- Issue Date: 2009